Dad?
爸？
Clear the ramp! 30 seconds! May God be with you!
e踝√板，三十秒後登 主保佑你
Port side and starboard side stick! Move fast and clear those mortar holes!
左舷右舷著，快攻着谂_
I want to see plenty of beach between men.
大家量分散
Five men is a juicy opportunity. One man is a waste of ammo.
五人就容易成槟 一人t能躲_
Keep the sand out of your weapons! Keep those actions clear!
e沙子堵塞口，小心行事
I'll see you on the beach!
在╊^上
Clear the mortar hole! Right and left!
避_坑，分成左右闪
Over the side!
到旁去
Port and starboard!
淖笥曳较滤
Thank yo...
xx
What now, sir?
L官，怎Nk？
I said, "What the hell do we do now, sir?"
L官，F在怎Nk？
Captain Miller! Captain Miller!
米勒上尉…
Captain Miller! Sergeant Horvath!
米勒上尉！霍瓦特中士！
Move your men off the beach! Now!
叫你的弟兄攻上╊^，快
Okay, you guys, get on my ass! Follow me!
大家我命令，跟著我_
Sir! What's the rallying point? Anywhere but here!
L官，集合c在哪e？ 之不是@e
What now, sir? The seawall, move up to the seawall!
怎Nk，L官？ 快攻上海堤
Sir, I'm staying! Clear the beach to make way.
我要留下恚∠裙╊^再f
This is all we've got between us and the Almighty.
走出去就死定了
Every inch of this beach has been pre-sighted.
@╊^的每一都被瞄柿
You stay here, you're dead men!
留下肀厮o疑
Mama, Mama!
…
Stay down, stay down!
伏下
What are you guys? 104th Medical Battalion, sir.
你是什N部？１０４的tI
We're here to set up field operations. Get rid of that crap!
我是碓O立t站的 G掉@U物
Grab yourselves some weapons and follow me.
拿起武器跟我
I'm hit! Briggs!
我中了！布格斯
Medic!
to兵
I'm hit low! God!
天啊，我中了！to兵
Navy Beach Battalion, sir!
我是海┐箨
I've got to clear these obstacles. Make holes for the tanks!
我得清除@些障K，樘箍碎_路
The armour is floundering at sea. Orders, sir!
b甲都掉到海e了 L官，@是命令
Go somewhere else! I'm clearing this one.
到e去，@e交o我
Come on, Briggs!
戆桑布格斯
Medic!
to兵
Move, move!
快走，快
Come on, move!
戆桑快
Shore party! No armour has made it ashore.
海岸後勤工作 b甲都o法登岸
We've got no DD tanks on the beach. Dog One is not open!
╊^上都]有DD坦克 D1缺口]打_
Who's in command here?
@e是l指]？
You are, sir!
L官，是你
Sergeant Horvath? Do you recognize where we are?
霍瓦特中士？ 你J得@是哪e幔
Where we're supposed to be, but no one else is.
是原定的集合c 但s]有支援部
Nobody's where they're supposed to be!
大家都走散了
Shore party!
海岸後勤工作
First wave ineffective! We do not hold the beach.
第一波攻o效 o法攻缀
Say again, we do not hold the beach!
重}，o法攻缀
We're mixed up! We've got people from Fox, Able and George companies.
我都混在一起了 @e有F、A和GB的弟兄
Plus, we got some Navy demo guys and a beachmaster.
和海爆破T及痍L
Shore party, Shore party!
海岸後勤工作…
CAT-F, CAT-F, CA...
指]官…
Reiben here. Seen anybody else?
Re蟮 有看到e人幔
Jackson, but that's it. Mellish here!
只有芸松 梅利西蟮
Caparzo! We've got DeForest back there with Wade!
卡帕佐 德佛e斯特和f德在後面
D.'s hurt so bad he's sprung a hundred leaks! Wade says he's used up!
他乐厥а，f德f他]救了
Move on to somebody you can help. Let go, he's a battalion surgeon!
去救其他人吧 我走吧，他是t
Get his attention! Wade!
去叫他！f德
Wade, don't do it! It's too risky, too risky, Doc!
f德，e@N做，太危U了
Get your ass back here!
快L回
Get him off the beach.
把他Щ
I've got it! We've stopped the bleeding!
我k到了，我替他止住血了
Fuck!
去你的
Just give us a fucking chance, you son of a bitch!
混蛋，sM⒔^
Wade, come on! You son of a fucking cocksucker!
f德，走吧 你@混蛋
Wade, it's Mellish. Wade!
f德，是梅利西，f德
Let's move! We found Miller! Let's move!
走吧，找到米勒了，走吧
Fuck it!
去你的
Get down, get down!
伏下…
This is all? This is all that's made it?
就只有你幔
We got scattered pretty bad. There's bound to be more of us.
我被分散了，一定有人的
It's not enough.
@硬
Dog One exit. It's the cut to the right, or was it left?
D1缺口是在右是左？
No. Vierville is to the left. This is Dog One.
不，SSe在左 @e才是D1缺口
They're killing us and we don't have a fucking chance! That ain't fair!
他在痛宰我 根本]有C痿Y，不公平
Gather weapons and ammo!
收集武器
Reiben! Where's your BAR?
Re？你的手呢？
Bottom of the Channel. The bitch tried to drown me.
在水底 差co耻害我被淹死
Find a replacement.
再去找一支
Bangalores! Bring out some bangalores!
拿爆破筒出
Engineers coming! Grenades, give me grenades!
工兵砹 o我手榴
Bangalores up the line!
把爆破筒\到前面去
Heads up! Bangers coming your way! Come on, come on!
小心，爆破筒砹耍戆
Jackson here, sir! Reiben back, sir.
芸松蟮 Re回砹
Oh, my God!
天啊
Mortars incoming!
迫襞砹
One more, give me one more!
再o我一支
Oh, my God, it hurts! I'm going to die!
天啊，痛死我了，我快要死了
Oh, my God! Jesus! Oh, my God!
天啊…
Come on, put it in. Keep it moving.
放M去，^m
We've got it.
行了
Jesus! Lucky bastard.
天啊，你\庹婧
Move it! Keep it moving!
快c
You're not going to die. You're fine. Just don't look at it. Don't look at it!
你不死的，e看
Bangalores! Clear the shingle!
用爆破筒砉簦_
Fire in the hole!
噬晨
We're in business! Defilade! Other side of the hole!
可以反攻了，找掩o 到沙坑的另一
Give him some morphine.
o他岱
That's it, let's go.
行了，走吧
Inspected, morphine.
z^了，注射岱
Routine.
一般理
Priority.
先理
Son of a bitch! Get in there.
混蛋，^去
Fuck, I can't move! Mellish, give me your bayonet.
可海我硬涣 梅利西，刺刀o我
Sarge.
中士
Two MG-42s, two mortars. Add 20, left 30.
赏MG-42C，芍迫襞 在前方二十a，左三十a
There's defilade, but it's a good firing position if we can land the armour.
那有掩o物，若b甲登後 是最好的l射位置
We've got to get this draw open!
我得打_@缺口
Reiben, Mellish! Let's get in the war! Take cover and put fire on that crew.
Re、梅利西，上吧 找到掩o就猛烈_火
Davis, DeBernardo, Young, Valk! Get ready!
大l斯、德伯{多 睢⑼呖耍】
Covering fire!
_火
Go, go, go!
去吧
It's a goddam firing squad.
耻的炮火很害
It's the only way we can get everybody out of here.
要逃出@e，只有@
Short, Payton, McDonald, Parkes! You're next!
肖特、佩森、唐{、帕克斯 你是下一M！
Why not just hand out blindfolds, Captain?
何不乾脆o我眼罩 不就行了幔
All we can do here is die! Covering fire!
唯有出去拼命，_火
Go, go, go!
快…
Come on, come on, come on! Go, God damm it!
快c… 去你的
Jackson. Sir.
芸松 是
That impact crater should give you defilade from the machine gun position.
看那坑幔 在那e能躲_C的攻
Get in there and give me some fire discipline. Wait for my command.
躲M去好好表F法 等我的命令
Go!
去吧
If your mother saw you do that, she'd be very upset.
若你看你@ 很n的
I thought you were my mother.
我以槟憔褪俏呢
Be not Thou far from me, O Lord.
ehx我，天主
Oh, my God. I am heartily sorry for having offended Thee.
主啊，很抱歉我曾激怒你
I detest my sins for having offended Thee, O Lord. Listen to me, Lord.
我Υ松罡邪没 我的\告
All my strength! Haste Thee to help me.
n我力量，助我抗
Dog One exit, right here!
D1缺口打_了，往@走
We're in business!
大家反攻
Move, move!
快
Reiben. Go, Sarge!
Re 去吧，中士
Come on, Doyle!
戆桑多e
Sarge!
中士
Flame! Doyle, do it!
多e，打_火器
Don't shoot! Let them burn!
e_，他吃吃苦^
On the right!
右
I'll give you "comrade", you son of a bitch!
你一起死吧，混蛋
Look out! Turn around, turn around.
小心，D^去
Flush them out!
去值羲
Cease fire, cease fire! Cut it out, cut it out!
停火…住手…
Cease fire!
停火！
Sugar Cane, Sugar Charlie Three. Say again, Dog One is open.
@是SC第3，重} D1缺口已打_了
Send in the dozers. I'm waiting here to tie in my flanks.
派出推土C 我在@e等待配合纫
What?
什N？
What? I'm sorry, I can't understand what you're saying!
抱歉，我不懂你在f什N
What did he say, what did he say?
他f什N？
Look, I washed for supper!
我洗^手涑燥了
Who's got a bazooka, goddammit?
l有火箭筒？真死
Hey, Fish. Look at this, a Hitler Youth knife.
笨蛋，你看 是希特勒青年F小刀
And now it's a Shabbat challah cutter, right?
F在是q太I包刀了，Π桑
Keep it moving!
e停下
That's quite a view.
好K烈的景象
Yes, it is.
]e
Quite a view.
很K烈
"Dear Mr Brian Boyd. No doubt by now you have received full information"-
“H鄣牟┮恋孪壬 你已得悉…”
"about the untimely death of your son."
“你鹤拥乃烙”
"No words can ever relieve your grief."
“f什N也o法 pp您的哀痛”
"Our outfiit has felt his loss greatly..." "He was a fiine soldier"-
“本部λ的死深感惋惜 他是秀的士兵”
"and believed strongly in what we were doing..."
“K深信我所氖碌摹”
"We were involved in one of the most important operations of the war."
“我⑴c了大鹬 最重要的事行印
"Al was the one who held us all together."
“艾使我能FY一致”
"He was the first to volunteer."
“他身先士卒”
"We passed a road where over 4,000 troops had passed."
“那e有四千人的部_^”
"Your husband served in a unit whose duty is to place itself beyond..."
“尊夫M忠守…”
"...which we all cherish and hold dear..."
“大家都很涯钏”
"The loss of Lee and others like him is a distinct blow to the regiment."
“李等人的死 F打羯醮蟆
"We understand your desire to learn about"-
“我t解你想知道…”
"the circumstances leading to his death."
“他去世r的情形”
Colonel, I've got something you should know about.
上校，有件事想告V你
These two men died in Normandy.
@扇嗽谥Z曼第亡
This one at Omaha Beach. "Sean Ryan."
@位死于W哈R海 肖恩瑞恩
This man at Utah. "Peter Ryan."
@位死於q他 彼得瑞恩
This man was killed last week in New Guinea.
@位上周在新亡
"Daniel Ryan."
丹尼瑞恩
They are brothers.
他是兄弟
This afternoon their mother is going to get all three telegrams.
他的在下午 接到@三封
There's also a fourth brother who parachuted in with 101st Airborne -
在┣耙煌 他的四弟跟S101空降
the night before the invasion. He is somewhere in Normandy.
在Z曼第某跳
Is he alive? We don't know.
他活著幔 不知道
Come with me.
跟我
Goddammit.
死
All four were in the same company in the 29th Division -
四兄弟都在第29的 同一B服役
but we split them up after the Sullivan brothers died on the Juneau.
但K利文兄弟在朱Z送命後 我便分_了他
Any contact with the fourth son, James?
能j上四弟詹姆斯幔
No. He was dropped 15 miles inland near Neuville, behind German lines.
不能，他空降在距~S15哩的 汝，深入了^
Mac, there is no way you can know where he was dropped.
根本o法知道他空降在哪e
First report from lke's people at SHAEF said the 101st is scattered.
101空降的人失散了
There are misdrops all over Normandy.
Z曼第有很多 被空投e`的部
Assuming Private Ryan even survived the jump, he could be anywhere.
就算瑞恩能安然降落 也o法找到他
In fact, he's probably K.I.A.
可能他早已亡
And frankly, if we go sending some sort of rescue mission, -
老f，若我派出搜救部
flat-hatting throughout German reinforcements along our advance, -
他就得穿越德固守^
they're going to be K.I. A, too.
那一定也亡的
I have a letter here...
@e有封信
...written a long time ago to a Mrs Bixby in Boston. So bear with me.
是很久以前o波士D的 比克斯比太太的信，我x
"Dear Madam."
“女士”
"I have been shown in the files of the War Department a statement" -
“我已穆樗_T塞州 上⒏惫俚摹”
"of the Adjutant General of Massachusetts" -
“部n案得悉”
'that you are the mother of five..."
“你是五位在沙錾稀
"...sons who have died gloriously on the field of battle."
“光s亡的鹗康哪赣H”
"I feel how weak and fruitless must be any words of mine" -
“我感到我的言o薄弱o力”
'that would attempt to beguile you from the grief' -
“根本o法安崮愕谋”
"of a loss so overwhelming..."
“也o法a你的p失”
"...but I can't refrain from tendering the consolation that may be found" -
“但我必要在此向你致x”
"in the thanks of the republic they died to save."
“他是榱苏救家而死”
"May our Heavenly Father assuage the anguish of your bereavement" -
“天主安崮愕首又痛”
"and leave you only the cherished memory of the loved and lost" -
“你永h涯钸h去的邸
"and the solemn pride that must be yours to have laid such a sacrifice" -
“神}的s耀都w於你”
"upon the altar of freedom. Yours very sincerely and respectfully," -
“因你樽杂 付出了重大的代r”
"Abraham Lincoln."
“林肯敬上”
That boy is alive. We are going to send somebody to find him.
那孩子活著 我要派人去找他
And we are going to get him the hell out of there.
然後他hx
The Quartermaster's up the beach a way. Look for a blown-up bunker.
後勤官在海 ふ冶徽У牡锉
Miller, Charlie Company. Go on in, Captain.
我是CB的米勒 上尉，M
If we don't off-load the Shermans by 0600 -
若六c以前o法下坦克的
we'll have a division stuck at Carentan with its pants around its ankles.
一整的部 就被困在卡坦
Well, you let me know of it.
再f明一下
Let Charlie Company hold at Vierville 'til we can get the armour there.
CB死守SSe 直到b甲兵_到
Runner!
髁畋
Airborne was supposed to win an open door for us, but misdropped, -
原本空降打_缺口的 但他s投e地方
and scattered all their sticks into the wind. What's your situation?
全都失散了，你的情r如何？
Yes, sir... Sector Four is secure.
第四^攻下了
We took out towed 88s here, here and here.
我摧Я诉@滋的 88公炮
They got four Shermans and some deuce-and-a-halves.
耻有四部坦克和一些\兵
These two minefields are actually one big one.
@商的牙^很大
We went up the middle of it, but it turned into a mixed high-density field.
我到了中心地 lF地雷的密度很高
A little bit of everything; Sprengmine 44s, Schumne 42s, -
什N地雷都有，S44型、S42型
pot mines, A-200s, the little wooden bastard the detectors don't pick up.
散片型地雷、A-200 By器都o法找到
Here, they placed big mushrooms, Teller mine 43s, I guess for our tanks, -
@e埋了T43型大地雷 大概想炸我的坦克
from here right up to the edge of the village, right here.
倪@e到村f的
We marked them and called the engineers.
已下位置，通知了工兵
Resistance? We had higher support expectations.
有遇上反抗幔 ]想像的那N
There was a company without artillery. Wehrmacht. 346th Infantry.
有一B]配大炮的346步兵
Von Lucke Kampfgruppe. We ended up with 23 prisoners.
由卡夫加帕指] 我俘了23人
We turned them over to MPs from the 29th.
已交由29的兵置
What about our casualties?
我的亡呢？
Well, the figure is... We're 35 dead, times two wounded.
亡人凳恰35死，70人
They just didn't want to give up those 88s.
他就是不肯放那些重炮
It was a tough assignment. That was why you got it.
任蘸芷D巨，所以才找你
Yes, sir.
是，L官
John...
s翰
I've got another one for you. Yes, sir.
你又有一任樟 是，L官
It's straight from the top.
是上直接交k的
I wish. You and I are taking a squad to Neuville on a PR mission.
我希望你和我б魂人 到~S去绦泄P任
Oh, are you leading a squad?
由你ш幔
A private in the 101st lost three brothers and he's got a ticket home.
一位二等兵死了三兄弟 所以能回家
Why Neuville? They think he's there.
楹我去~S呢？ 他X得他在那e
Part of all those Airborne misdrops.
他是被e投的空降部之一
It won't be easy finding one soldier in the middle of this goddam war.
F在兵荒Ry 要找一名士兵很y
Like finding a needle in a stack of needles.
就像大海漆般
What about the company?
那B上兄弟怎Nk？
We take the pick of the litter, the rest goes to Baker.
最好的跟我 其他的加入BB
Jesus Christ! They took away your company?
天啊，他Z走了你的B？
It wasn't mine, it was the Army's. So they told me, anyway.
部是方的，我唯有遵命
Get me Reiben on BAR, Jackson, Wade, Beasley and Caparzo.
o我Re、芸松、f德 斯e和卡帕佐
Beasley's dead. Alright, Mellish then.
斯e死了 那找梅利西
Do have a guy who speaks French? Not that I know of.
有人法Z幔 我所知]有
What about Talbot? This morning.
塔博特呢？ 今早死了
I'm going to try and dig up another interpreter.
我要去找翻gT
Assemble at the battalion motor pool on the beach.
到╊^的v{度黾合
What are we going to do? Listen up. What?
怎Nk？ 著，什N？
Go home wrapped in the American flag with a hunk of cheese in your ass.
我要用大K乳酪塞M你的屁股 好你棺材w旗回家
I thought you liked it in the ass. What?
我以槟阆g塞屁股的 什N？
Attention!
立正
As you were. I'm looking for Corporal Timothy Upham.
稍息，我要找提摩西厄本下士
Yes, I'm Upham.
是，我就是厄本
Do you speak French and German? Yes, sir.
你f法Z和德Z？ 是，L官
How's your accent? Slight one in French.
有]有口音？ 法Z有
My German's clean. Very good.
但德Z很正 很好
You've been re-assigned to me. Grab your gear, we're going to Neuville.
你已被派o我了 收拾行囊，我要到~S去
When was this updated? As of 8:30 this morning.
@是何r更新的？ 早上八c半
This is the 12th SS Panzer. These are the two axes advancing south.
@是12SS坦克部 有申人向南推M
There are Germans in Neuville. I understand, Corporal.
~S有德 我知道，下士
There are a lot of Germans in Neuville. You've got a problem with that?
~S有很多德 有}幔
Please consider that I've never been in combat. I make maps and translate.
我]作疬^ 只懂Lu地D和翻g
I need someone who speaks French and German.
我需要法Z和德Z的人
My two guys were killed. I haven't held a weapon since training.
原淼晌魂亡了 我男卤後就]拿^
Did you fire the weapon in Basic training?
基本r_^吧？
Yes, sir. Well, then get your gear.
_^，L官 那去湟幌
Sir, may I bring...
L官，我能А
May I bring my typewriter, sir?
能Т蜃C幔
Yes, sir.
是，L官
Thank you very much.
xx你
Is that a souvenir? No, sir.
那是o念品幔 不是
Take your time.
慢慢
You should look on the bright side of things, Corporal.
下士，凡事都有好的一面
Yes. For one thing, you don't need those.
是 有，@也]有用
You'll need that. Yes. I'll need this, not that.
但你需要@ Γ要@
Hey!
你好 致铮
You want your head blown off?
你是不是想找死？
Don't touch me with those rat claws again. Get the fuck back in formation!
e再用你的爪子碰我 回去你的位
I was just wondering where you're from.
我只是想你碜阅难e
Caparzo, is it? Drop dead, Corporal.
卡帕佐，Π桑 L_，下士
Gotcha.
知道了
Every time you salute the Captain, you make him a target for the Germans.
每次你向上尉敬Y 就惹淼萝u羲
I'm sorry. Do us a favour. Don't do it.
Σ黄 兔Γe那N做
Especially when I'm standing next to him. Capisci?
尤其是 我站在他旁r，懂幔
Capisco. Corporal, what's your book about?
懂了 下士，那是什N？
Watch your rifle. Sorry.
心你的 Σ黄
It's about the brotherhood that develops between soldiers during war.
是P於行r l展手足之情的方法
Brotherhood? What do you know about brotherhood?
手足之情？ 你懂什N是手足之情？
Get a load of this guy, Fish.
要注意@礅
Why don't you ask the Captain where he's from?
你何不去上尉是哪e人呢？
Ask the Captain. He'll tell you everything you want to know about him.
去他，他什N都告V你的
Explain the maths of this to me.
解o我
Where is the sense in risking the lives of the eight of us to save one guy?
八人楹我 冒U救一人呢？
20 degrees. Anybody wants to answer that?
20度，有人想回答幔
Reiben, think about the poor bastard's mother.
Re，想想那可zx的吧
Hey, Doc, I've got a mother.
to兵，我也有
You've got a mother, Sarge has got a mother.
你有，中士也有
Shit, I bet even the Captain's got a mother.
我敢f上尉也有
Maybe not the Captain, but the rest of us.
也S上尉]有，但我全都有
"Their's is not to reason why their's is but to do and die"
“不原因，只求奚”
La-la-la... What the fuck is that supposed to mean, Corporal?
下士，那是什N鬼意思？
We're all supposed to die?
我都死幔
Upham's talking about our duty. Yes, sir.
厄本f的是我的 是，L官
We all have orders to follow.
我全都得服拿令
Yes, sir. Thank you. Even if the mission is "FUBAR"?
是的，L官，xx 就算任帐恰翱嗖睢保
Especially if the mission is "FUBAR".
@才更加要服
What's "FUBAR"? It's German.
“苦差”是什N？ 是德Z
Never heard of that...
]^
Sir, I have an opinion on this matter.
L官，我Υ擞悬c意
By all means, share it with the squad.
f出砺吧
From my way of thinking, -
我的想法是
this mission is a misallocation of valuable military resources.
@次任 浪M了F的事Y源
Yeah? Go on.
是幔坷^m
It seems to me that God made me a fine instrument of warfare.
我X得上帝no我打仗的天分
Reiben, pay attention. Now, this is the way to gripe. Continue, Jackson.
Re，好，@颖г共 ^m，芸松
If He was to put me and this sniper rifle anywhere up to and including -
要是他派我@狙羰
one mile of Adolf Hitler with a clear line of sight, sir...
到希特勒一哩
Pack your bags, fellas, the war is over. Amen.
大家就能收拾行囊回家 就Y束了，阿
That's brilliant, bumpkin.
l巴佬，@主意不e
What about you, Captain? You don't gripe at all?
上尉，你呢？你不抱怨幔
I don't gripe to you. I'm a captain. There's a chain of command.
我是上尉，身重任 不向你抱怨
Gripe always go up.
上永h是l牢}的物件
You gripe to me, I gripe to my superior officers, and so on.
你向我l牢} 我向我上l牢}，如此推
I don't gripe in front of you. You should know that as a Ranger.
我不在你面前l牢} 你是突絷T，明白
I'm sorry, but let's say that you weren't a captain or that I was a major.
Σ黄穑就你不是上尉 或我是少校吧
What would you say?
你f什N？
In that case, I'd say, "This is an excellent mission" -
那游揖f @任瞻O了
"with a valuable objective worthy of my best efforts."
意x重大，值得我全力以赴
"Moreover, I feel heartfelt sorrow for the mother of Private Ryan" -
而且我θ鸲鞯哪赣H 感到深切的悲痛
"and I'll lay down my life and those of my men, especially yours, Reiben," -
榱宋拷逅 我意r上我c部下的性命
'to ease her suffering."
尤其是你，Re
He's good. I love him.
他很棒 我喜g他
Fine!
算了
Thunder! Flash!
打雷！ W！
Upham, over there. Reiben, you four go.
厄本，到那去 Re，你四^去
Go, go, go, go!
去吧！
You are a sight for sore eyes. Sergeant Hill, our reliefs showed up.
很高d看你 希中士，救星砹
How many are you? Eight. We're not your relief. Sorry.
有多少人？ 八，但不是救兵
What do you mean, sir? We're here for a Private Ryan.
槭颤N？ 我碚叶等兵瑞恩
Who? Ryan? What for?
l？ 瑞恩？槭颤N？
Is he here? Maybe on the other side of the town.
他在@e幔 大概在的另一
It's hard to get to. The Germans punched a hole in our centre.
周都有德，很y通^
They cut us right in two. What's his name, again?
我o德切 他叫什N名字？
Ryan, James Ryan. He dropped in with the 101st.
瑞恩，詹姆斯瑞恩 `101空降
Goldman, get me a runner! Runner!
高德曼，找髁畋 髁畋
Come on!
戆
Jonesy, make a hole up there!
斯，_
We got stopped by fire from the eastward.
我|面的炮火所阻
The Germans have been reinforcing two regiments all day.
德聚集了F的兵力
It's been quiet for 45 minutes.
已有四十五分]有屿o
The Germans concentrate their fire westward.
德正把火力集中於西面
Who's that on the loudspeaker? Dagwood Duesseldorf.
l在V播？ _伍德迪撒多夫
Our friendly neighbourhood morale officer.
友善的政鸸
"The Statue of Liberty is kaputt."
“自由神像完蛋了”
That's disconcerting.
想_y我心
Your father was circumcised by my rabbi, you prick!
笨蛋，你爹的包皮已o割掉了
Cover!
躲好
Go!
去吧
You sadistic fucking animals! Get down.
去你的臭混蛋 伏下
They know we're not in direct contact. They'll single out the runners.
橙酥道我通中 所以髁畋
Why do they shoot them up?
槭颤N要射⑺？
As long as his lungs are working, he carries the message. We'd do the same.
不能留活口，以防情外泄 我也@幼
No, we wouldn't! Wade! Get them ready to travel.
不，我不 f德，淦鸪
Boyd! Come on!
博伊德 戆
Try again! Let Captain Hamill know we're coming.
再一遍，O法通知 h米上尉，我正s^去
What's the rest of Neuville like?
~S其他地方怎N樱
The next block's got two-storey buildings. A lot of windows.
接著看到咏êB物 有很多窗
There's a square with good cover.
有一V隹勺鞑厣碇用
Show me. Sarge, hold right here!
我去，中士，留在@e
Yes, sir!
遵命
Stay out of this enfilade and use the buildings.
e在@e挨打，到e面躲避
Try a left hook. Shoot and scoot. Two of yours, two of mine.
到左去，走_火 我各派扇
Hastings, Goldman! Up front!
黑斯亭斯、高德曼，到前面去
Reiben, Caparzo. They're still jamming us.
Re、卡帕佐 通仍受耻干_
Short runs, high and low at the corners. It's going to be tight.
快到角落去，小心行事
Be prepared for close contact. Go.
溥M行近身穑去吧
Upham! You stay with Sergeant Horvath.
厄本，跟霍瓦特中士待在一起
Stay here! I'll wear him like underwear, Captain. You stay with me.
上尉，我像妊般粘著他
Past the end of the block are the gates of the square.
V鲩l口在大堑谋M^
Good. Alright.
好 好的
Reiben, where's the Captain from?
Re，上尉哪难e淼模
If you figure it out, you'll get a prize. 300 bucks, last I heard.
猜中的有 金三百K
The company's got a pool. Five bucks gets you in.
大家下注，最少五K
It's around this corner. Defilade right up to those gates.
就在拐，躲到lT後面去
Somebody must know where he's from.
一定有人知道他碜院畏
I've been with him since Casserene Pass. I don't have a clue.
我跟他一起那N久也毫o^w
My ankles are killing me. I'll need a wheelchair before the war is over.
我的足踝很痛 鹗]Y束已要坐椅
That's it! Oh, my God! That ankle is like an old woman.
老天，就跟老D一
Like an old... Oh, God!
就像…老天
Reiben. So you don't even know where he went to school?
Re？你B他上哪所W校 也不知道？
He didn't go to school. They assembled him at OCS out of dead Gls.
他]念 是部用大兵企wMb而成
Pay attention to detail. I know where he's from and what he did -
我知道他的v
because I pay attention to detail.
因槲铱吹米屑
Hey, Upham! Careful you don't step in the bullshit.
厄本，e信他的鬼
Do it. Thunder!
去吧 打雷
Thunder, or we will fire on you!
打雷，不然_火
Mellish, Caparzo, come here!
梅利西、卡帕佐，^
Tell them to show themselves.
叫他表明身分
Ask them where the Germans are.
德在哪e
What is he saying? Something about the children.
他f什N？ 孩子
Kids? He wants us to take them.
孩子？ 他想我ё吆⒆
No, no. We can't take the kids.
不行，不能ё吆⒆
We can't take the kids! No, no!
不可以，不行
They think they'll be safe. They won't be safe with us!
他以檫@虞^安全 跟著我不安全
Are you nuts? Listen to the Captain!
你了？纳衔镜拿令
They think they'll be safe with us.
他以楹⒆安全一c
It's not safe anywhere. Caparzo! Put that kid back!
什N地方也不安全 卡帕佐，交回孩子
Caparzo, put the girl back! It's OK, it's OK.
卡帕佐，把孩子o他 放心
Give that kid back!
交回孩子
Upham, how do you say, "It's OK?" I can't. She reminds me of my niece.
厄本，怎Nf放心？ 他我想起外甥女
Get the kid back up there!
把孩子交回去
We should at least take her to the next town.
最少也把她У较市
We're not here to do that, we're here to follow orders!
我有任赵谏 不是砭群⒆
Sarge, take this goddam kid!
中士，把孩子接^
Cover, cover!
躲好
No!
糟糕
Goddammit! Where did that come from?
可海哪e射^淼模
He was on the ground before we heard the shot.
到前他已倒地
That's where I'd be.
是我就到那e
I didn't see it. 450 yards, maybe a shade under.
我看不到 450a外，也S在暗
I wouldn't venture out there, fellas. This sniper's got talent!
大家e冒U出去 那手很害
Please don't cry. I'll take you back to Mama and Papa. Please don't cry.
e哭，我你找爸
Come on.
戆
Carpy!
卡帕佐
Captain! Hold on, Caparzo.
上尉 沃，卡帕佐
Help me up. I can walk.
扶我起恚我走得
Caparzo, stay still!
卡帕佐，e
Two clicks. Left wind.
筛瘢L向偏左
Fish!
笨蛋
Captain, can you see him? How is he?
上尉？看到他幔克怎N了？
Wade, you stay put.
f德，ey
Where is he shot, Captain?
上尉，他哪e中？
Can you see him? You stay there!
看得到他幔 e出去
Damn it! Stay down!
可海躺下
What's the matter with you? Am I going to take care of you if you get hit?
你怎N了？你中了 要我照幔
Fish, come over here!
笨蛋，^
Carpy, put your head down! Why can't you put your head down?
卡帕佐，躺下e
Oh, my God, I trust in Thee.
天主，我信靠你
Let me not be ashamed. Let not my enemies triumph over me.
e我蒙羞，e橙傥
Copy it. Copy it and send it for me.
抄下恚替我寄出去
You're going to send it yourself. Put it down!
放下恚你自己寄
It's got blood on it! I see it.
信沾了血 我知道
It's... It's to my dad. It's got blood on it, Fish.
o我爸的，沾了血，笨蛋
We got him. Stay down.
打中了，伏下
How bad is it? Chest, maybe lung shot.
得很重？ 胸口中，或S肺o打中了
Get that.30 up the street!
把大炮放到街上
Detail! Clear, up!
蟾媲r 上面安全
Clear, down!
下面安全
That's why we can't take children.
老早f^不能Ш⒆
Sergeant Horvath, do an ammo check.
霍瓦特中士，z查武器
Upham, canteens. Fill them up.
厄本，把水匮bM
Sergeant Hill. Yes, sir.
希中士 是的，L官
Gather your men. We'll form up at the northwest corner of the square.
召集弟兄，在V鑫鞅苯羌合
Jackson. Sir!
芸松 是
Mellish. Check the tower, hustle back here. Right now, go!
梅利西，去z查那座塔 快回恚快去吧
Fuck Ryan!
去他的瑞恩
Thunder! Flash! Come on in!
打雷 W，M戆
Hey, guys. We're looking for Captain Hamill.
我在找h米上尉
Down there, across the square. Across the square.
那，^了V鼍偷 ^了V
Go easy. Watch for snipers.
提防狙羰
Sit down.
坐
Jimmy T. Go and find Captain Hamill. Bring him here.
吉米，叫h米上尉^
What? Up there? How should I know? Go and look!
什N？上面幔 我怎N知道？自己去找
Thank you, you moron.
xx你，智障
Alright. You guys just flake out here for a while.
先在@e休息一下
Let me get this goddam hitchhiker out of my boot.
我要把石子倒出
Put your weapons down! Drop them now!
放下武器 立刻放下
I'll shoot you!
我_的
Drop, drop 'em!
放下武器
Put 'em down!
立刻放下武器
Clear, up!
上面安全了
Shit, shit!
可
Clear, down!
下面也安全了
Enough to make you old.
@幼蜃人老了
Let's hope so.
但如此
Hamill, Pathfinders 101st. Miller, 2nd Rangers.
101前Р筷的h米 第二突絷的米勒
Thank you.
xx
We're looking for a Private Ryan. He's part of your outfit.
我在找二等兵瑞恩 他是你的傧
Any chance that you policed him up?
有可能找到他幔
How was the road in? Scenic. We lost most of our ammo.
路上的情r如何？ L光明媚，快用光了
Not to mention one of our men.
死了一位T
Lieutenant! Redeploy that bazooka to the right side of the road.
中尉 把火箭筒{Q到右的路旁
And get Ryan up here!
去瑞恩^
Ryan! Ryan! Front and centre! Ryan!
瑞恩…到前面
Here comes our boy.
我的大砹
I told you he was an asshole.
我早f他是混蛋
Private Ryan reporting as ordered. At ease.
二等兵瑞恩蟮 稍息
Captain Miller, 2nd Rangers, wants a word with you.
第二突絷的米勒上尉 有跟你f
This way.
@
Alright. Take a knee.
蹲下吧
Private, I'm afraid I have some bad news for you.
二等兵，有南息要告V你
Well, there isn't any really easy way to say this, so...
@真是人y以X…
...so I'll just say it. Your brothers are dead.
我就直f吧，你的兄弟死了
We have orders to come and get you...
我奉命碚夷
...because you're going home.
你可以回家了
Oh, my God! My brothers are dead!
老天，我兄弟死了
I was going to take them fishing when we got home.
我本想他去~的
I'm so sorry, James. I can't tell you how much.
Σ黄穑詹姆斯 真是不知f什N
How did they die? They were killed in action.
他是怎铀赖模 亡
That can't be.
]有可能
They can't be my brothers. They're still in grammar school.
他才在念中W
You're James Ryan? Yeah.
你是詹姆斯瑞恩？
James Francis Ryan from lowa?
郯⑷A州的 詹姆斯法m西斯瑞恩？
James Frederick Ryan, Minnesota.
明尼K_州的 詹姆斯腓德利克瑞恩
Does that mean my brothers are OK? Yeah, I'm sure they're fine.
那表示我弟弟]事幔 Γ我_信他很好
Are you sure? We're looking for a different Ryan.
你_定？ 我找的不是@瑞恩
It's just a big foul-up.
只是`而已
How can you be sure? How do you know that the foul-up isn't -
你怎N能_定？ 怎N知道是不是又弄e了
that his brothers are OK, and...
原硎撬的弟弟]事
Lieutenant. I'm sorry for the trouble.
中尉 麻┠懔
I just wrote them a letter before I left. I've got to get home.
我在x_前才o他信 我得回家去了
I've got to get home right now. I want to go home.
我要立刻回家，我想回家
Where is our Ryan? Don't know.
我的瑞恩在哪e呢？ 不知道
Are you in touch with your CO? What unit's Ryan in?
可以跟指]官j一下幔 瑞恩`凫妒颤N挝唬
Baker Company, 506th. The guy with the broken foot's in 506th.
506F的BB 那嗄_的礅肥506F的
Charlie, I think. You think?
我想是CB吧 你想？
Ryan? Don't know... Man!
瑞恩？我不知道…老天
Where was your dropzone? Vierville.
你在哪e降落？ SSe
Vierville? How did you end up here?
SSe？那怎到@淼模
You got me, sir. The C-47 took heavy fire.
倒我了 C-47受到猛烈的攻
Pilot went crazy turning every which way.
C拼命W避炮火
We took more fire in the drop. It got messy. I ended up here.
跳r炮火更猛 情r混y，我就砹诉@e
I haven't seen anyone from my stick. God knows where they are.
我]^我的友 天缘盟在哪e
Did anybody from Baker Company talk about where the dropzone was?
有BB的人到空降^在哪
No, but they had the same rallying point as us.
]有，但大家的集合c一
Show me.
指出
My men are beat. We'll hold up here for three hours and pull out after dark.
我累透了 再待三小r，入夜後出l
Got anything left in this town, like a three-star hotel?
@上有三星店什N的
Something with clean sheets, soft pillows and room service?
有乾Q的床巍⒄眍^ 和客房服幔
How about a nice, comfy church? We'll take that.
舒m的教堂如何？ 也好
What have you heard? How is it all falling together?
有什N消息？r如何？
We got the beachhead secured, but Monty's taking his time moving on Caen.
我攻下了╊^堡 但蒙蒂s慢l斯理的M康城
We can't pull out 'til he's ready, so... That guy's overrated.
要他浜梦才能撤 大家高估他了
No argument here. You take Caen to take Saint-L8.
我同意 要拿下康城才能攻取}_
You gotta take St-L8 to take Valognes. Valognes, you've got Cherbourg.
要攻取瓦隆尼先要拿下}_ 瓦隆尼之後是瑟堡
Cherbourg, you've got Paris. Paris, you've got Berlin.
瑟堡之後是巴黎 最後是柏林
And then that big boat home.
然後就能回家
I could really use you around here, but I understand what you're doing.
你在@e能偷轿液芏 但我t解你的任
You do? I've got a couple of brothers myself.
是幔 我也有兄弟
Oh. Good luck.
原硎沁@ 祝你好\
Thank you. No, I mean it.
xx 不，我是f真的
Find him. Get him home.
找他出恚他回家
What's with your hand?
你的手怎N了？
I don't know.
不知道
It started in Portsmouth when we went down for embarkation.
在阗Y茅斯上船後就是@
It comes and goes. You have to find yourself a new job.
偶@ 你找e的工作
This one doesn't seem to agree with you any more.
@工作不m合你了
What?
致铮
Nothing.
]什N
What was the name of that kid at Anzio?
在安W那小子叫什N名字？
The one who walked on his hands -
用手倒立走路那
and was singing that song about the man on the flying trapeze?
唱著空中w人之歌那？
Vecchio. Vecchio!
SYW
Yeah, Vecchio. He was a goofy kid.
不e，他是笨蛋
I remember he used to pee a "v" on everybody's jackets. For "vecchio".
喜g在e人的外套上尿出 一“V”字，代表SYW
For victory. Vecchio.
代表倮 SYW
He was so short. He was a midget, wasn't he?
他L得很矮 是侏儒吧？
Yeah, how did he get to be a Ranger?
那他怎N能上突絷T？
He got shot in the foot once, walking on his hands.
他的_o打嗔 所以用手走路
He could walk faster on his hands.
走得很快
He could run faster on his hands.
跑得更加快
Vecchio. Yeah.
SYW
Caparzo.
卡帕佐
You see, when you end up killing one of your men, -
每一位弟兄死去
you tell yourself it happened so you could save the lives of -
就要告V自己，@幽苷救
two, three, or ten others.
二、三、四或十l人命
Maybe 100 others.
甚至是一百人
Do you know how many men I've lost under my command?
你知道我指]r 有多少部下亡幔
How many? 94.
多少？
But that means I've saved the lives of ten times that many, doesn't it?
但那代表我救了 十倍那N多的人幔
Maybe even 20, right? 20 times as many?
甚至是二十倍？
And that's how simple it is.
事情就是@N
That's how you rationalise making the choice -
就是@影讶张c傧轮g
between the mission and the men.
所做的x窈侠砘
Except that this time the mission is a man.
但@次任照是救人
This Ryan had better be worth it.
@瑞恩最好值得我去救
He'd better go home and cure some disease -
他回家後最好能行t救人
or invent a longer-lasting light-bulb or something.
或l明L襞菔颤N的
For the truth is that I wouldn't trade ten Ryans for one Vecchio or Caparzo.
我想十瑞恩也抵不了 一卡帕佐或SYW
Amen.
阿
Look, there it goes again. Sir.
你看，又砹 L官
Are you alright?
好吧？
We'll move out in two hours. Why don't you get some sleep?
尚r後出l？小睡片刻吧
I don't know how he does it. What's that?
不知道他怎N能做到的 什N？
Falls asleep like that. Look at him.
如此熟睡，你看
The guy's lights-out the minute his head hits the pack.
他躺下就睡著了
Clear conscience. What's that saying?
因心o愧 有句怎Nf？
God's on our side, who could be on theirs?
神c我同在 那lc耻同在？
"If God be for us, who could be against us?"
若神c我同在 l是我的κ郑
Yeah, what did I say?
不e，我f了什N？
The trick to falling asleep is trying to stay awake.
想睡著的，保持清醒就行了
How is that, Wade?
槭颤N，f德？
When my mother was an intern she used to work through the night -
我tr T在夜g工作
and sleep through the day.
白天睡X
The only time we talked was when she'd get home.
只有她回家，我才能聊天
I used to lie in bed and stay awake as long as I could, but it never worked -
我躺著，量保持清醒 但]成功^
because the harder I tried the faster I'd fall asleep.
越不想睡，就越快睡著
That wouldn't have mattered in my house. Ma would've come home, -
但在家e]PS 因回家
shook me awake, chatted me up 'til dawn. She was never too tired to talk.
把我弄醒，聊至天亮 聊天r她是不嫌累
That's probably the only time she could get a word in.
也S她在那r候 才有Cv
Funny thing is, sometimes she would come home early -
有趣的是 有r她下班rg早了
and I'd pretend to be asleep.
我假b睡著
Who, your mum? Yeah.
l？你？
She'd stand in the doorway looking at me, -
她站在T口看著我
and I would just keep my eyes shut.
我就]眼b睡
And I knew that she just wanted to find out about my day, -
我知道她特地早些回
that she came home early just to talk to me.
跟我聊天，t解那天的生活
And I still wouldn't move. I'd still pretend to be asleep.
但我s仍然不 假b已熟睡
I don't know why I did that.
我也不知道楹那幼
We've only got a couple of hours. Shut up and go to sleep.
只有^，]嘴睡X吧
Captain? Sir?
上尉？L官？
Corporal.
下士
How are you doing? Are you alright?
你怎N了？]事吧？
Yeah, I think this is all good for me, sir.
好，我想@一切ξ矣幸
Really? How is that?
真的？槭颤N？
'War educates the senses, calls into action the will," -
“能判嗔 磨意志”
"perfects the physical constitution," -
“增w格”
"brings men in such swift and close collision in critical moments," -
“人在生死P^的瞬g”
'that man measures man."
“弱立判”
I guess that's Emerson's way of finding the bright side.
勰森也S是 @幼自己eO起淼
You know Emerson, sir? I know some.
你也有x勰森？ 懂一些
So, where are you from, Captain? What did you do before the war?
上尉，你碜阅难e？ 在鹎澳闶亲鍪颤N的？
What's the pool up to?
金有多少了？
I think it's around 300, sir.
大概是三百K吧
When it gets up to 500, I'll give you the answer and we'll split the money.
等到了五百的r候 我就把答案告V你，瓜分金
How about that?
如何？
If that's the way you feel, I feel it's my duty under your command -
要是你@N想 我就有任建h你
to suggest that we wait until it gets up to 1,000. I think it's...
等金累e到一千K
What if we don't live that long?
要是活不了那N久呢？
500? 500 would be good, yes.
五百？ 五百好
Yes, sir.
ΓL官
Get some sleep, Corporal.
睡吧，下士 是，L官
Who's got sulfa powder?
l有磺胺粉？
Medic, my buddy's bleeding! He needs a tourniquet.
to兵，我弟兄在流血 需要止血
Wade. Yes, sir?
f德 什N事？
See what you can do. Yes, sir.
去退一下 是
Hold on, fellas. It won't be much longer.
沃，很快就有人砭饶
How are we doing here?
情r如何？
Alright. You're doing alright, don't worry about it. The Doc's in town.
]事的，e心，t砹
Don't worry. The 29th Infantry's breaking through. They'll be here soon.
放心，29步兵F已作突 很快到@e
Has anybody got plasma?
l有血{？
Hey, Captain!
上尉
Soldier, you want to fill me in? Yeah. Lieutenant DeWindt.
有什N事幔 我是德氐弥形
99th Troop Carrier Squadron carrying in 300th and 307th Glider Infantry.
`凫兜99\兵中 \d300c307滑翔C步兵
This one was mine. I was the pilot. Private!
我是w行T 二等兵
22 men dead. Take care of this one.
22人亡 照他
I landed there without a scratch, took my co-pilot's head right off.
我著r]受 副{s死了
Who are these people?
@些人是l？
The guys we came in with headed off the first night. Haven't seen them since.
我d的士兵第一晚就x_ 之後]再^他
In the meantime other guys keep showing up. One, two, six at a time.
期ge的士兵 三五成群地m出F
Then some officer will come along, patch together a mixed unit, -
然後有官戆焉⒈成部
and head off to make trouble.
再次出l作
We're looking for a Private Ryan, Baker Company, 506th of the 101st.
我在找101 506BB的二等兵瑞恩
You got me. A lot of guys come in and out.
@可倒我了，@e人砣送
Upham! Check out that squad. See if Ryan's in it.
厄本，到那人e面找瑞恩
Yes, sir.
是的，L官
Reiben! Smell that leg, right there. Find out if it's south of cheese.
Re，他的腿 像不像臭乳酪
What?
如何？
Hands over your head.
手放^上
Keep moving!
e停下恚
I'm Jude, you know.
我是q太人
I couldn't pry him out of there. I need a winch.
o法把他弄出恚要有g
Yeah.
是的
Stars.
星上
Brigadier General Amend. Deputy Commander, 101st.
阿T 101空降的副指]官
Some genius had the great idea of welding steel plates onto our deck -
有些天才提h 在C焊接板
to keep the General safe from ground fire, -
以免地面的炮火及上
but they forgot to tell me until just before we were getting airborne.
但他到空降前才告V我
That's like trying to fly a freight train. OK?
就像_\列w行般？
Gross overload. Trim characteristics all shot to hell.
荷^重，地面炮火又猛烈
I nearly broke both my arms trying to keep her level.
我榱吮３制胶 手缀醵寂嗔
When we released I cut as hard as I could, -
勾r我已M力了
trying to gain some altitude and keep her from stalling.
L保持高度，以免失速
We came down like a fucking meteor. And this is how we ended up.
最後像E石一拥粝 Y果成@
The others stopped easy enough, though.
其他wC算利著
We were just too damn heavy, you know?
我的wC太重了
The grass was wet. Downward slope and all.
草地窕，而且是下坡
22 guys dead.
死了22人
All that for a general? One man.
全榱艘上？ 一人
There's a lot of that going around. "FUBAR."
@N事很多 “苦差”
You all got that right.
都fα
I looked it up in a German dictionary. "FUBAR"'s not there.
我在德Z字典中 查不到“苦差”
Upham! There are more paratroopers out there.
厄本，那也有惚
Find out if one of them is Ryan.
去找瑞恩
You might want to check this out, sir.
你可在@e找找
Dog tags. More than I really want to count, sir.
是兵籍牌，多得挡煌
I've covered a lot of bodies, sir.
我已w^S多企w
Jackson. Start going through those. Yes, sir.
芸松，倪@些_始找吧 是
I'll help.
我兔
Do you think that little prick's in there? If he is, I'm going to find him.
你X得有那小子幔 有的，我找到的
I bet that son of a bitch... I've got money saying he's still alive.
我敢f那混蛋… 我打他活著
10 bucks says I nail him first. Let's see what we've got in here.
十K我先找到 砜催@e有什N
You mugs don't stand a chance. Do you think he's in here?
你]希望了 你J樗在@e面幔
Just keep looking. Alright.
^m找吧 好吧
"Gary lanico", "Ben Rubino", "Mike Cesario"...All the Guineas are buying it.
w瑞艾尼高、班瑞比Z 克塞eW，全都是人
Come on, it's not the right name! 'Wee Willie Winkie". A buddy of yours.
不是@名字 SSeS琪，是你的朋友
We've got to find this prick.
我得找到那混蛋
Where's this son of a bitch?
那混蛋在哪e？
Don't mix them up. Keep them in your pile.
e混在一起，分_一c
How am I supposed to know who we've got?
怎N知道哪些是看^的呢？
Why don't you just shut up, Reiben?
Re，]嘴好幔
Everybody be friends. Cranky there, huh?
e吵架 你不高d幔
I think I've got a winner. What are you talking about?
有僬吡 你f什N？
"Ryan." Ryan?
瑞恩 瑞恩？
Take a look at that, Mellis. You're really a genius.
梅利西，你看 你直是天才
"R-l-E-N-N-E." That's "Rienne" and it's French. Do you know what that means?
@是e恩，是法Z名字 知道@是什N意思幔
It means "nothing". What beats three of a kind?
一o所@ 什N比三l大？
I got shit here, all guys from New York. You're always bitching.
@些人全都碜约~s 你老是l牢}
Do you need a hand? I've got a full house.
要兔幔 我葫J
I've got you beat. Straight flush.
我A了，同花
You're looking at my cards. You're cheating.
你偷看我的牌，你作弊
Fucking unreal, this guy. Can you read that shit?
笨得太xV了，你R字幔
Jesus, look at this poor bastard! I guess they're not bulletproof.
老天，你看@可z的礅 大概不能防吧
I guess not.
不能
I don't like what's between his ears. It's like what's between your legs.
@礅]X袋 跟你的那e一
We've got to give him that. That's not bad for you, Jackson.
O了 芸松，f得]e
I've got three of a kind. What the hell are you doing?
我三l 你在致铮
The whole goddam Airborne's watching. These aren't poker chips.
整空降都在看著 @可不是淇伺
Alright. Put them back in there.
好吧 放回去
He's not here.
他不在@e
Maybe we should split into groups?
也S我分^去找吧？
Just wander the woods calling his name.
到淞盅e去叫他的名字
He's bound to hear us sooner or later. Ryan!
他t早到的，瑞恩
That might be a little hard to do, Captain.
上尉，@也不是k法
Maybe the locals have seen him. Ryan, James Ryan?
也S本地人^他 瑞恩，詹姆斯瑞恩？
Ryan! Anybody know Ryan, 101st Airborne? You know Ryan?
瑞恩？有人JR 101空降的瑞恩幔
Private James Ryan from lowa? Anybody know a Ryan?
郯⑷A州的二等兵瑞恩？
James Ryan! Hey, Joe!
瑞恩 阿
Doesn't Michaelson pal around with a Ryan from C Company?
可森不是JRCB的瑞恩
I think so. Bring him up.
是 他^
You know Private Ryan? You have to speak up...
你JR二等兵瑞恩？ 你要大一c
You have to speak up, sir! My hearing is not so good!
大一c，我的耳朵不`光
It comes and goes. A grenade went off right by my head.
手榴在耳朵爆炸 力r有ro的
Got it. Do you know Private Ryan? Who?
你JR二等兵瑞恩？ l？
Private Ryan? James Ryan? Jimmy Ryan?
二等兵瑞恩？詹姆斯瑞恩？ 吉米瑞恩？
James. James Francis Ryan.
詹姆斯法m西斯瑞恩
No, no, no. James Francis Ryan.
不，是詹姆斯法m西斯瑞恩
Give me a pencil. Something to write on.
o我P
Quick, a pencil!
快c，UP
Here you are, a small one.
小UPo你
Write this down: "James Francis Ryan? lowa?"
下恚詹姆斯法m西斯瑞恩 郯⑷A州？
"Do you know him?" Read the message! Look!
你JR他幔磕阕约嚎
Yeah, of course I know him. Does he know where he is?
我然JR他 知道他在哪e幔
Yeah, we missed our dropzone by about 20 miles -
我偏x了降落^二十英里
and ended up way over by "Bumville" or some damn place.
降落的地方好像是 布Se什N的
Him, me and a couple of others were coming here to the rally point.
我跟他和其他人 正要到了@e集合
We ran into a colonel who was gathering up men to go to Ramelle.
s遇到一位上校 正召集弟兄前往m姆勒
Ramelle? To babysit a bridge.
m姆勒？ 去防守一座
That's the last I've seen of him. Great! Thank you!
那是我最後一次看他 好O了，xx
Write "Thank you". Read. Thank you. You're welcome!
xx，你看，xx 不客
Assemble on me.
大家^
Thank you, Lieutenant.
xx你，中尉
Ramelle.
m姆勒
We're here. There. Ramelle is on the Merderet River, right here.
我在@e m姆勒在德里特河畔
Just to the southwest of us.
在我的西南方
You know anything about that bridge?
你知道那座幔
Yeah. The target has always been Cherbourg.
知道，瑟堡一直是盟的目
We can't push on Paris until we take a deep water port and Rommel knows that.
要最I深水港，才能攻装屠 而隆美也知道
He's going to try to get his armour across the Merderet River anyway he can.
他著把b甲部 \^德里特河
That way he can hit us in the flank when we make the turn for Cherbourg.
@泳湍茉谖 M攻瑟堡rA粑
That makes any village on the river with a bridge solid gold real estate.
所以有诺拇迩f 都成了重要的c
Let's go.
走吧
Captain.
上尉
What the hell is that?
那是什N？
A radar site. It's got to be out of action.
U的雷_站
Looks like we've got something in that sandbag bunker under the station.
下I的沙坑e有橙
See it? Yeah, that's my guess, too.
看到幔 Γ我也@N想
What is it? Machine gun, probably MG-42.
那是什N？ C，或S是MG-42
Is that what got those guys? Maybe one of them is Ryan.
那些人就是被它值舻模 也S瑞恩也在e面
No, their patches are 82nd, so your luck's not that good.
不，他是82的 你的\獠]那N好
I don't know how fast you are, but if we detour this way quick and quiet, -
我不知道你的_程 但若我悄悄地@道
the Krauts will never even know we were here.
德就不知道我在@e
What I'm trying to say is why don't we just go around the thing?
楹尾焕@道走？
I hear what you're saying, but we can't go around it.
我明白，但不能蜻@
I'm with Reiben. I mean, we left those 88s.
我支持Re的f法 避_那些C就行了
For the Air Force. They're not going to spend ordnance on one machine gun.
空可不３ Ω兑煌C
Captain.
上尉
We can skip it and still accomplish our mission. This isn't our mission, right?
@路是能_成任 @K不是我的任眨Π桑
Is that what you want to do, Mellish?
梅利西，你想@幼幔
Leave it here so they can ambush another company?
任由其他部中伏？
No, I'm simply saying it's seems an unnecessary risk given our objective.
不，我只是f @K非我的目
Our objective is to win the war.
我的目耸谴僬
It's just that I don't have a good feeling about this one.
我有不安的A感
When was the last time you felt good about anything?
你何r有^好的A感了？
Alright. Three runners with suppressing fire.
好吧，三人_前_火
Mellish. You hook to the right, I'll go up the middle.
梅利西，你跑右，我跑中g
Who's going left?
l跑左？
I'll do it.
我去
I go left. Alright.
我跑左 好
Upham, switch off with Jackson and you linger in the rear.
厄本，跟芸松φ{ 而你待在後面
We advance and keep pressure on him 'til he has to change out his barrels.
我向前猛攻，迫他Q子
We should be able to hit them from grenade range.
然後就扔手榴
Maybe I should go up the middle? The way you run? I don't think so.
也S我跑中g？ 你那N跑法？我想不必
Maybe I should go left, sir. Maybe you should shut up!
也S我跑左 也S你]嘴
Reiben, base of fire.
Re，管_火
Mags and clips where you can reach them -
把г谏磉
and extra grenades for the base runners.
主攻的多些手榴
Hill's clear. Four down and dead! Upham!
山上安全了，值袅怂 厄本
Grab the gear and get up here! We need water and extra dressing.
收拾b上 我需要水和物
Get the morphine out of the medical kit!
乃包e把岱饶贸
Son of a bitch! Get some sulfa on there.
混蛋 撒上磺胺粉
Move my legs up. I got them.
把我的腿抬高 行了
Pour sulfa. Listen to my voice.
快倒磺胺粉 我f
You're going to be alright, Doc.
你]事的，t
You're fine. You're going on a hospital ship.
]事的，很快就能上t船
More sulfa! Move my legs up.
倒多一c 把腿抬起
Put my legs up. I've got them.
把腿抬高 行了
You're going to be OK. It's alright, Doc.
你]事的 ]事，t生
Upham, give me your canteen! Come on.
厄本，把水亟o我！ 快
We're going to get you out of here. Put some pressure on it.
我你x_的 褐口
Am I shot? How does it look? Give him some morphine.
我中了？萑绾危 替他注射岱
How does it look? You're going to be OK.
萑绾危 你]事的
Here comes the morphine.
要注射岱攘
Am I shot in the spine?
被射中脊椎了幔
You're OK.
]事的 是不是射中脊椎？
Lift him up. Move him over.
抬起他 把他翻^去
Put some pressure on. Easy, easy.
褐口 pc
It's OK, Doc. It's alright.
]事的，t生
Wade, you've got an exit wound. It's in the small of your back.
f德，子穿了出去 你背後有孔
How big is the hole? It's about the size of an acorn.
那洞有多大？ 像橡果那N大
It's fine. Put him back.
好了 放下他
Put some pressure on it.
鹤口
Put some more pressure on it.
用力一c
Is there anything bleeding worse than the others?
哪e流血^多幔
Yeah, right here. Do you know what it is? Right here.
有，@e 知道在哪e幔窟@e
I'll put your hand on it. We got some pressure on there.
我把你的手放到上面 我正褐口
That's the one.
就是@e
Oh, my God! My liver! It's my liver!
天啊，那是我的肝K
Tell us what to do. Tell us how to fix you.
教我怎N救你
What can we do? Tell us what to do.
我怎Nk？告V我
I could use a little morphine.
o我一c岱
More morphine, sir.
多一c岱
OK. OK.
好
Sir? What? Give it to him.
如何？ o他吧
I don't want to die! Here you go, Wade. Here it comes.
我不想死 f德，我正在注射
Give him another one.
再注射一
Mama...
…
I want to go home, I want go home.
我想回家…
Reiben, hold him!
Re，抓住他
Not yet!
等一下
First make him mark and cover Wade's body for Grave Detail.
先叫他替f德掘
Same thing for the paratroopers down there.
也替那些惚掘
Strip that stuff off him. Check him for intelligence.
拿走他的b洌查他
Ask this piece of shit if he shot Wade! Ask him!
@混蛋，f德是不是他⒌ 快
Does it matter? It does!
有用幔 有
Shut up with that filthy pig Latin.
]上你的v嘴
Jackson, are you hit?
芸松，你中了幔
It just skinned the arm.
只是擦T了
Get it cleaned and dressed. You and Sarge watch the perimeter.
把口理好 你跟中士留意周
He says, "Please don't shoot." I don't care what he says, Upham.
他求我e⑺ 厄本，我不管他f什N
Sir? Sir, are you going to let them kill him?
L官？你要他⑺？
This is not right, sir. You can help him with the bodies.
@是不Φ 那你去退埋企w
What is happening?
怎N了？
American.
美人
I like American.
我喜g美人
Steamboat Willie.
船威e
Steamboat Willie. American.
船威e，美人
He says he's not finished. That's what you think. Come on.
他f他]完成 那是你的想法，戆
Please! I like America!
求求你，我喜g美人
Fancy schmancy! What a cinch!
美什N都好
Go fly a kite! Cat got your tongue! Cool beans!
美什N都有
Betty Boop! What a dish.
蒂小姐，好性感
Betty Grable. Nice gams.
蒂嘉，腿很美
I say can you see
我f你看到幔
I say...
我f…
Fuck Hitler.
去你的希特勒
Sir, he says he's sorry about Wade. He says he's sorry about Wade.
L官，他f他替f德y^…
Captain!
上尉
Captain, this isn't right. You know this.
上尉，你也知道@幼霾Φ
He's a prisoner. He surrendered. He surrendered, sir!
他是鸱，他已投降了
Tell him...
叫他…
...to march 1,000 paces in that direction. Then he can take off the blindfold.
朝那方向走一千步 然後掉蒙眼布
He turns himself in to the first Allied patrol.
向盟自首
Are you kidding? We're letting him go?
你在f笑幔糠潘走？
He's a POW, Reiben. We can't take him with us.
Re，他是鸱 不能е他走
Our guys will pick him up. That was a close shave.
我自置他 算他命大
Lucky Strikes.
真幸\
Take me out to the ball game...
我去看球
Only if he doesn't get picked up by his own and get thrown back into circulation.
f一他被耻救回 又回碜鸬
Captain, you just let the enemy go. This is such bullshit.
上尉，你白白放^了橙 直白V
You all got that right. Bullshit? This is bullshit?
]e 白V？@是白V？
Shooting a prisoner is OK? It's against the rules!
y道可以射鸱？ @邮怯羞`法的
The goddam rules just walked off with your new friend.
法跟你的新朋友一起走了
But I guess that was the decent thing to do, Captain?
上尉，@幼鍪Φ陌桑
Get your gear. Let's go.
收拾|西，出l吧
You heard him. Gear up.
你到了，收拾|西
The Captain just gave you an order. Yeah.
上尉下了命令
Like the one he gave to take this machine gun. That was a real doozy.
就像他下令攻下C台一 真是大英雄
You're out of line!
你太^分了
That was one hell of a call coming to take this nest, -
他命令我拿下@e真是英明
but what the hell, we only lost one of our guys going for it.
但我s因此适Я艘晃魂友
I hope Mama Ryan's really happy knowing that little Jimmy's life -
瑞恩一定很高d 知道她的小的性命
was more important than two of our guys!
比我晌魂友的重要
But then, we haven't found them, have we?
但我]找到他吧？
Hey... Get off me!
你… e碰我
Reiben, get up.
Re，起
Gear up. Fall in.
拿起|西，入列
I'm done with this mission.
我要退出@任
Hey! Hey!
等等
Sir... Don't you walk away from your captain!
L官… 你不能背上尉
Reiben, get back in line! No, sir.
Re，o我回 不
I'll spend the rest of my life in the stockade rather than go on.
我可坐牢也不想^m了
I'm not going to ask you again. Captain!
我不再你的了 上尉
This is bullshit! Fall in!
白V 入列
Are you going to shoot me over Ryan? No, because I don't like you.
你要因槿鸲鞫⑽遥 不，是因槲矣你
If he wants to go, just let him go!
他想走，就他走吧
Are you letting this happen? Captain! You see this?
你不管幔 上尉，你看到了幔
Captain. Sir, Ryan's dead.
上尉，瑞恩已死了
Bullshit! We have a situation here.
白V @e情r不妙
I have a sixth sense. I know it in my bones.
我有很的第六感
We didn't kill the Kraut. Now you're going to shoot me.
你不⒌萝s要⑽遥
He's better than you. Just do it!
他比你好 下手吧
Put one in my leg... I'll shoot you in your big mouth!
打我的腿… 我要打你的大嘴巴
Put your money where your mouth is and do it!
U少f，_吧
You don't know how to shut up.
你是那N多f
Captain, please! What's the pool on me up to?
上尉，求求你 金有多少了？
You are a coward son of a bitch! I'm waiting, Sarge.
你是懦弱的混蛋 中士，我在等你_
What's the pool on me up to right now?
金累e到有多少了？
What's it up to?
有多少了？
What is it? 300 dollars, is that it?
三百K幔
I'm a schoolteacher.
我是老
I teach English Composition...
我教英文作文
...in this little town called Addley, Pennsylvania.
在e夕法尼州一叫 艾德里的小
In the last 11 years, I've been at Thomas Alva Edison High School.
@十一年砦以 斯鄣仙高校任教
I was the coach of the baseball team in the springtime.
在春季我是棒球教
I'll be doggone.
我真死
Back home, when I tell people what I do for a living -
我在家l告V人家我的Ir
they think, 'Well, that figures."
他X得“一看就知道”
But over here, it's...
但到了@e
...a big, big mystery.
s成榱艘大秘密
So, I guess I've changed some.
我想我了一c
Sometimes I wonder if I've changed so much -
有r我想我改了很多
my wife is even going to recognise me whenever I get back to her...
回家後也S妻子不J得我
...and how I'll ever be able to...
或S我不能向她…
...tell her about days like today.
Vf像今天@N事情
Ryan...
瑞恩
I don't know anything about Ryan. I don't care.
我θ鸲饕o所知，我才不管
He means nothing to me, it's just a name, -
他跟我毫oPS 那只是名字
but if going to Ramelle and finding him so he can go home, -
但要是到m姆勒他回家
if that earns me the right to get back to my wife, then...
能我回到妻子身
...then that's my mission.
我接下@任
You want to leave? You want to go off and fight the war?
你想退出？你想去作穑
Alright.
]PS
Alright, I won't stop you. I'll even put in the paperwork.
我不阻止你 我甚至替你申
I just know that with every man I kill, the farther away from home I feel.
我只知道每多⒁人 我就x_我的家越h
...by memories of days gone by
昔日的回ガF
In my solitude you taunt me
孤中你嘲弄我
with memories that never die
勾起不死的
I sit in my chair filled with despair
我坐在椅上，M呀^望
There's no one could be so sad
比任何人都要哀
With gloom everywhere I sit and I stare
看著坐著的地方 M是霾
I know that I'll soon go mad
我很快就掉
Half-track! Cover!
有坦克，躲好
Who's doing the shooting?
是l_？
Get ready to move. Take their left flank!
湫樱攻糇筮
Hold on and make sure they're down.
慢著，提防有p
101st! We're coming out!
我是101，要出砹
That was a recon. element, 2nd SS.
b甲兵第二
We've been expecting a probe. That must have been it.
我正在等待情 一定是他了
Captain Miller, Charlie Company, 2nd Rangers.
第二突絷CB米勒上尉
Corporal Henderson, Easy Company, 501st.
501EBh德森下士
Ryan, First of 506th. Toynbee, Third of 506th.
506F第一瑞恩 506F第三托恩比
James Francis Ryan? Yes, sir. How did you guess that?
詹姆斯法m西斯瑞恩？ Γ你怎N知道？
Looks like you got hit pretty hard. Yes, sir. Small unit action.
看撤焦菝土 Γ是小M部的M攻
They came in and beat the hell out of us with 88s.
他的88公炮威力
Tell you what. If you're our relief, I'm going to file a complaint.
要是你就是救兵 我可要投V
I wouldn't blame you.
我不怪你
Who's your CO?
l是你的指]官？
It would've been Captain Jennings.
原本是甯斯上尉
I'm afraid the best we can muster up now is a corporal.
但F在唯有以下士充指]
So what are you guys all about?
那你楹磉@e？
We're here for him. Ryan.
我樗而恚瑞恩
Me, sir?
我？
James Francis Ryan of lowa?
你是郯⑷A州的 詹姆斯法m西斯瑞恩吧？
Yes, sir. Peyton, lowa, that's correct. What is this about?
Γ郯⑷A州佩D市 @是怎N回事？
Your brothers were killed in combat.
你兄L亡了
Which ones?
哪？
All of them.
全部
On the level?
真的？
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
恐怕是真的
You might want to take some time with this.
大概要一段rg才能接受
If there's someplace you want to go and...
要是你想到什N地方…
What's this all about? Ryan lost his brothers.
是怎N回事？ 瑞恩的兄弟去世了
Which one? All of them.
哪？ 全部
You came all the way out here to tell me that?
你３膛砀嬖V我？
You're going home.
你要回家
Our orders are to bring you back.
我奉命你回去
Bring me back?
我回去？
Corporal, I don't mean to leave you more short-handed, but orders are orders.
下士，我K非想落井下石 但令如山
Any communications about when you will be relieved?
想跟什N人j幔
We can't tell. We don't know what's happening south of us.
我也不知道南方的情r
My orders don't include me abandoning my post.
但我的命令不S我擅x守
I understand that, but this changes things.
一切以@道命令作
I don't see that it does, sir.
我不J同
The Chief of Staff for the US Army says it does.
@是美⒅\L的命令
Our orders are to hold this bridge at all costs.
我奉命死守@座
Our planes in the 82nd have taken out every bridge across the Merderet, -
我方C已把德里特河的 所有耪
with the exception of two: one at Valognes and this one.
除了瓦隆尼和@e商
If the Germans take it, we'll have to displace.
要是o德拿下 我就要退守
Private. It's one thing that your outfit wants to stay, but your party's over here.
部的任帐且换厥 但你要x_了
I can't leave before the reinforcements are here.
援到_前我不能x_
You've got three minutes to get your gear.
三分仁帐靶醒b
What about them, there's barely... Hey, asshole!
那他怎Nk 混蛋
Two of our guys already died trying to find you.
我晌魂友已槟闼兔
Sir? That's right.
真的？ 不e
What were their names? Irwin Wade and Adrian Caparzo.
他叫什N名字？ 艾文f德和艾德林卡帕佐
Wade and?
f德和l？
Caparzo.
卡帕佐
It doesn't make any sense.
]有理由要@
It doesn't make any sense, sir. Why do I deserve to go?
@]道理 我何德何能，可以先走？
Why not any of these guys? They all fought just as hard.
楹尾皇撬？ 他也同优力
Is that what they're supposed to tell your mother -
你死後饔T就要跟…
when they send her another folded American flag?
你母H@诱f？
Tell her that when you found me I was here, -
跟她f你在@e找到我
and I was with the only brothers that I have left, -
我要跟中其他手足一起
and that there was no way I was going to desert them.
我怎右膊x他
I think she'll understand that. There's no way I'm leaving this bridge.
她明白 我不x_@座
What are your orders?
F在怎Nk？
Sergeant, we have crossed some strange boundary here.
中士，我M入了 一奇的度
Our world has taken a turn for the surreal.
一切都乎こ
Clearly, but the question still stands.
但}始K要解Q
I don't know. What do you think?
我不知道，你X得怎樱
You don't want to know what I think.
你不想知道
No, Mike, I do.
不，我想知道
Part of me thinks the kid's right. What's he done to deserve this?
我其中一想法是 如他所言，他何德何能？
If he wants to stay here, fine. Let's leave him and go home.
他既然想留下 我就乾脆回去
Yeah.
不e
But another part of me thinks, 'What if by some miracle we stay" -
但我有一想法 要是我也留下
"and actually make it out of here?"
造什N奇E呢？
Some day we might look back on this and decide that -
有天我回想此事
saving Private Ryan was the one decent thing we pulled out of -
也SX得在@龌中
this whole godawful, shitty mess.
拯救瑞恩是唯一的好事
That's what I was thinking, sir. Like you said, Captain.
@是我的想法 上尉，如你所言
We do that, we all earn the right to go home.
我留下 一起F聚痿Y
Oh, brother...
兄弟
This is everything.
就只有@些
You've got the.230 calibre machine guns, 17 grenades, 11 Hawkins mines.
0.230C、17枚手榴 11霍金斯地雷
You've got two bazookas, but they've only got eight rounds left.
你有芍Щ鸺筒 但只能l射八次
And assorted small arms.
有各式小手
We had a.60 mortar, but an arty round took it out.
本碛0.60迫襞冢但已p
Might as well be spit wads if they roll on us with tanks.
耻坦克哼^ 吐口水攻艉昧
Which they're sure to do. What are you thinking, sir?
耻然佑锰箍 你意下如何？
I'm thinking I'm going to whip around the flanks.
我提hM行A
Unless we can draw them up the main road between the buildings, -
要把他引到大街
where all the rubble makes a bit of a bottleneck...
用瓦[造一瓶i
Disable him? If we can.
坦克o用武之地？ 可以的
Make a 60-tonne roadblock. Then we've got a fighting chance at her flanks.
造六十的路障 然後展_A
Good. Split them up, don't let them mass.
好，分散他，e他集Y
Hit them hard one-on-one, and fall back to the bridge.
然後逐一羝疲再退回大
Machine gun on the move down here, number two up high to piss on them.
下I放一台C 另一台置於高
That would be the idea. Jackson!
就是@樱芸松
If we can, I'd like to get you up in that bell tower.
可以的，我想你去
Yes, sir. I'll give you some company.
知道 我o你安排褪
Some company couldn't hurt. A.30 with about a 1,000 rounds would be OK.
也好，要0.30狙 和一千l子
Parker, job opportunity.
派克，有份差
It's not the worst idea ever, -
@主意不e
but everything depends on getting the tank down the road for us to knock out.
但儇PI在於 把坦克弄到街上我A
How the hell do you plan on doing that?
你有什N主意？
He's right. As our colleague from Airborne pointed out -
他f得Γ空降的友f
what we've got is a bunch of spit wads.
我有的是口水
How do we stop the tank if we get it to commit?
但把坦克引磲幔如何付？
Give it a rabbit to chase.
先用兔子引它追s
We could hit the tank in the tracks.
接著攻籼箍说穆
Yeah, but with what?
Γ但用什N攻簦
We could try a sticky bomb. Sticky bomb, sir?
用粘附式炸 粘附式炸？
Sir, are you making that up?
你出淼陌桑
No, it's in the field manual. Check it out, if you want to.
不，你可以去翻翻作鹗
We seem to be out of field manuals. Perhaps you could enlighten us.
手圆恢道在那e 你管v解一下
You have some demolition, don't you? TNT or Composition B?
有炸吧？S色炸 是B成分炸？
Plenty. I've got that bridge wired with enough Composition B to blow it twice.
很多，蚰茄e的B炸 足以把蛘纱
You can spare some, then.
那拿一c出
You take a standard GI sock, cram it full with Composition B, -
塞Mbm子
and rig up a simple fuse. Then you coat the whole thing with axle grease.
再加MЩ鹁，表面TMC油
That way, when you throw it, it should stick.
炸扔出，就能粘附於目宋
It's a bomb that sticks. It's a sticky bomb.
有粘力，所以叫粘附式炸
Come up with a better way to knock the tracks off a tank, I'm all ears.
有更好的方法，管f出
This is good. Now we have to surrender our socks!
@主意不e，大家要Um了
Haul away.
拉上去
Select the field of fire. Crossfire with the one in the bell tower.
x窆艄 c墙M成交叉火力W
I can cover 12 to 9 from here.
我12到9
Easy! I've got her!
慢慢 行了
Here are the mines.
@是地雷
For being the best we can do, -
要配置得才行
that forward machine gun is not in a terrible firing position.
前^的C位置不太好
And this position right here...
放到@e
This is the Alamo.
@是最後防
They push us this far, the last man alive blows the bridge.
要是退到@e 最後一活人炸
We've only got a 30-second delay on the fuse, so tell everyone -
Щ鹁能三十秒，告V大家
that if you're last you'd better hurry or you'll not live long.
c火後快逃，不然性命不保
Captain? Where am I during all this?
上尉？我有什N任眨
Never more than two feet away from me. And that's not negotiable.
留在我捎⒊咧龋不S有h
I'm going to get some ammo. Come on.
跟我去拿
Hey, Upham, listen to me. Yes.
厄本，著 是的
Are you listening?
你在幔
We're going to be displacing and falling back like crazy sons of bitches, -
我不|奔西跑
so you've got to be Johnny-on-the-spot with the ammo, or we're dead.
你要\送，S麟S到 不然我就死定
Do you understand? Johnny-on-the-spot.
你明白幔 S麟S到
Yeah. Are you alright? Yeah.
你]事吧？ ]事
When we shipped out of England we got cigarettes -
我挠出lr 也分l香
and I said, "No, thank you. I don't smoke."
我sf“xx，我不抽”
Quite a situation, huh? Unbelievable.
形莺措U吧？ y以置信
Yeah. "Fucked-Up Beyond All Recognition", right?
@差事混さ貌坏昧
You've got that right.
不e
"FUBAR"! Alright!
“苦差”
Ouch.
很痛
Yeah, well... It's going to be a real show, huh?
@可不是玩的
Yeah, OK.
知道了
Take it easy.
放p
"FUBAR."
“苦差”
Who's that singing, sir?
是l的歌？
Edith Piaf.
艾迪斯皮雅福
What is she so upset about?
她楹芜@N心？
Her lover left her, but she still sees his face everywhere she goes.
情人x 但他的面容vv在目
That would do it.
就是@
"Even life itself only represents you."
生命中就只有你
"Sometimes I dream that I'm in your arms."
糁你砦胰
What was that? She sang it before. The chorus.
什N？她曾唱^ 是副歌
"And you speak softly in my ear."
每你耳Z喃喃
"And you say things that make my eyes close."
都我]目o
"And I find that marvellous."
感X美妙
Again, Upham...
厄本
...to be honest, I find myself curiously aroused by you.
老f，你使我d^莫名
Marvellous.
棒O了
It's a really melancholy song. At the beginning of the song she says:
@首歌很哀，_始r她唱著
"And then one day you left me and I've been desperate ever since."
你x去後，我就心^望
"I see you all over the sky, I see you all over the earth."
漫天M地，都是你的影子
Any more songs like this, the Krauts won't have to shoot me.
再多资走@N歌 不用德_
I'm just going to slit my own wrists.
我就割}自⒘
You're a strange bird, Upham.
厄本，你好奇怪
I'm sorry. It's Edith, you know.
Σ黄穑是艾迪斯
You know what that song reminds me of?
可知道@首歌我想起什N？
Mrs. Rachel Troubowitz and what she said when I left for Basic.
瑞雪太太在我出l前的一番
What? "Don't touch me?"
她f“e碰我”？
No. She's our Super's wife.
不，她是公寓管理T的妻子
She comes into my mum's shop to try a few things. She's like a 44 Double E.
她到我的店I衣服 胸有44EE
Double E? They're massive.
不得了
Those are big titties.
好大的奶奶
I've got her convinced that she's a 42 D. So we're in the dressing room -
我_她穿42D的衣服 我在更衣室e
and she tries to get into this side-cut, silk-ribboned, triple-panel girdle -
她LDM那件z束腰
with the shelf-lift brassiere.
有神奇胸罩
It's beautiful. She's pouring out of this thing.
很好看，都D了出
Is it tight? No, it's beautiful.
很o幔 不，很好看
She sees me and can tell I've got a hard-on the size of the Statue of Liberty.
她看得出我的小弟 像自由神像般又大又硬
She says, "Richard, calm down", and she says, -
於是她叫我冷o
"Over there, if you see anything that upsets you, if you're scared," -
又f要是在錾想y^害怕
"I want you to close your eyes and think of these, you understand?"
就]眼想想它
So I said, "Yes, ma'am."
我f我明白了
Are you alright, sir?
你]事吧？
Yeah, I'm just keeping the rhythm.
我在蹬淖
Is it true you were a teacher back home?
你在老家真的是老？
Yes. That's something I could never do.
我是不上老的了
Not with the way me and my brothers treated our teachers. No, sir!
我家兄弟都不老的
I had a thousand kids like you.
我教^上千你@拥暮⒆
I can't see my brothers' faces.
我想不起哥哥的容貌
I've been trying and I can't see their faces at all. Has that happened to you?
怎优力也想不起 你^@幔
You've got to think of a context.
你要想想l生^的事
What does that mean?
那是什N意思？
You don't just think about their faces, you think about something specific, -
不能只想他的幼 要想些具w事情
something you've done together.
你的共同v
When I want to think of home, I think of something specific.
我想家的r候，想得很具w
I think of my hammock in the backyard, -
我想起後院的吊床
or my wife pruning the rose bushes in a pair of my old work gloves.
或者是妻子戴起我的f手套 修剪玫瑰花
This one night, two of my brothers woke me up in the middle of the night.
有一晚哥哥把我弄醒
They said they had a surprise for me.
f要o我@喜
They took me to the barn up into the loft -
他我到Y}w
and there was my oldest brother Dan -
原泶蟾绲つ帷
with Alice Jardine!
跟劾蚪zZ汀在e面
Picture a girl who just took a nosedive from the ugly tree -
想像一下，那女孩囊恢 h陋的渖系粝
and hit every branch coming down!
所有渲Χ冀o
And Dan's got her shirt off...
丹尼去她的r衫
So he's trying to get her bra off and all of a sudden Sean screams out:
接著要把胸罩也下r 肖恩突然大叫
"Danny, you're a young man. Don't do it!"
“丹尼，你年o小 不可以@印
Alice Jardine hears this and she screams and jumps up -
劾蚪zZ汀R上大叫 跳了起
and tries to run out, but she's got her shirt over her head.
想_出去 但她的^or衫蒙著
She runs into the wall and knocks herself out.
所以撞到壁，倒了
Now Dan is so mad at us. He starts coming after us, -
丹尼很生猓追著我
but at the same time Alice is unconscious. He's got to wake her up.
但劾蚪z倒了，他要弄醒她
He grabs her by a leg and drags her -
於是一手抓著她的腿猛拉
and at the same time he picks up a shovel and goes after Sean!
一手拿著P子追s肖恩
And Sean says, 'Why are you trying to hit me? I just did you a favour!"
肖恩f“你致锎蛭遥 我是在湍恪
This makes Dan more angry. He tries to swing this thing.
丹尼更加生猓y]P子
He loses his shovel. It goes out of his grasp and hits a kerosene lantern.
最後P子手，打破了火油
The thing explodes. The whole barn almost goes up because of this thing.
爆炸著火，Y}缀踅o掉
That was it, that was the last... Dan went off to Basic the next day.
@就是最後一晚 丹第二天就上鋈
That was the last night the four of us were together.
@是四兄弟最後一次共聚
That was two years ago.
已^了赡
Oh, my.
天啊
Tell me about your wife and those rose bushes.
再ff妻子和玫瑰花驳氖
No. No, that one I save just for me.
不，那些事要留o自己
Enemy from the east.
橙|面_
He sees two Tiger tanks, two Panzer tanks.
商虎式坦克，奢vb甲
Infantry. 50 plus change.
五十人以上的步兵伍
Disperse! You know what to do. Reiben, get on the rabbit.
分散，各就各位 Re，去兔子
Upham, get some cover. Mellish and Henderson, lock and load!
厄本，躲起 梅利西、h德森，溟_火
Everybody check your ammo!
大家z查武器
Good luck, Reiben! I don't need any luck, I was born lucky!
Re，祝你好\ 不用祝福，我生硇疫\
One in five tracer. Yes, and tracers point both ways.
拿著五枚曳光 知道，照亮啥
Why don't you check the head space and she should run.
去z查端的空g
Upham, hustle up!
厄本，快c
Corporal Upham. We don't have a.30 calibre machine gun here.
厄本下士，@e]有0.30C
Either Mister Mellish or Mr Jackson in the bell tower needs that.
梅利西和堑 芸松才需要@
Upham! Jackson's fine, turn around to Mellish!
厄本，芸松有子 去拿o梅利西
There's a ton of infantry. I don't know if they took the bait, though.
有很多步兵，不知道否上
Have you got any more of that?
有口香糖幔
The Panzers didn't take the bait.
b甲]有上
The infantry's moving to the left.
步兵F正向左Ml
A half-track just went by with about 20 troops.
一vb甲跟二十人_^
Mellish, Henderson! Displace!
梅利西、h德森，移位
Do it, now! Light it up! You! Light it!
c火
30 infantry on the right flank. Get over there, find a hole and stop them!
右有三十人，O法截停他
Displace!
移位
Upham!
厄本
Clear! OK, go!
目饲宄 去吧
Krauts!
德人
Right flank!
向右M攻
Get down, get down!
伏下
Upham! Thirty cal, hurry!
厄本，0.30子
Find the Captain, this flank's going to fold!
告V上尉，左翼快失守
Traversing! He's still in this fight!
子在
No! Ryan, get down, get down!
瑞恩，伏下
Ryan!
瑞恩
Keep your mouth shut Get off me!
]嘴 放_我
Are you alright? Get off of me!
你]事吧？
I'm fine too, Captain. Thanks.
上尉，我也]事，xx
Hit them from both sides. Get aboard! Get a grenade in there!
A羲，扔手榴^去
Grenade!
手榴
20 mill! 20 mill!
是二十毫米C
Flak gun, 20 mm. Take it out!
是重型C，值羲
Heavy weapon in defilade below! I ain't got a shot!
Co覆w著，打不到
Pincer move! Parker! Targets eight o'clock, low!
Q子形，派克 目嗽诎它c方向
God grant me strength.
天主n我力量
Let's go, displace! Come on!
去吧，移位
Cover! Upham, cover!
厄本，躲好
I'm out of.30 calibre.
0.30子用光了
Blessed be the Lord my strength, which teaches my hands to war -
天主n我力量，教我的手打仗
and my fingers to fight.
教我的指^作
My goodness and my fortress. My high tower and deliverer.
天主是我的堡 我的高塔和解者
My shield and He in whom I trust.
我的盾牌，我的依靠
Here you go, baby.
去吧，
Parker, get down!
派克，伏下
Captain, that 20 mm is killing us.
上尉，那C很要命
We've got to try to flank it somehow. Let me get over there for a top shot.
一定要У羲 我到上面去
Upham!
厄本
Upham, Upham! Upham, ammo, goddammit!
厄本，拿子
I'm jammed! Got any.30 calibre? I'm out.
卡住了，拿0.30子o我 用光了
Upham. Upham!
厄本
Reiben!
Re
I'm out! I need another bandolier. Anybody got a bandolier?
用光了，有人有子幔
You piece of shit!
混蛋
Let's stop, let's stop! Listen to me! Stop! No, no, no...
住手，我f，e@
Fuck!
去你的
Son of a bitch, son of a bitch!
混蛋…
Son of a bitch!
混蛋
I'm out! Those.60 rounds...
用光了 那些0.60炮…
We can use them without the tube. How?
]有炮管也可以用 怎佑茫
Fuse-arming wire, set back and heave it!
@是引爆，扔出去就行了
Panzer schreck!
德人
Go, go!
去吧
We're going to the Alamo.
到最後防去
Alamo! Alamo!
最後防
We'll take it. You fall back! You be right behind us!
交o我，你撤退 你跟著
As soon as we're in business.
我很快回
Displace. Reiben!
Re，移位
Reload!
b
Alright, go!
_炮
We're blowing the bridge! Get off! Off the bridge!
要炸蛄耍快逃 快x_
Sarge! Mike, are you alright?
中士，克，你]事吧？
I just got the wind knocked out of me. Let's go!
被L吹倒了 走吧
Take cover, we're going to blow this bridge!
躲好，要炸蛄
Come on!
戆
Tiger company's coming across the bridge.
虎式坦克要^蛄
Captain, get behind something!
上尉，找地方躲好
Mike!
克
Captain, where the hell are you going? Captain, get back here!
上尉，你去哪e？回
Upham!
厄本
Hang in there.
沃
Medic!
救oT
Medic! We've got a medic?
有救oT幔
They're tankbusters, sir. P-51s.
是P-51反坦克Z炸C
Angels on our shoulders.
我的守o天使
What, sir?
什N事？
James...
詹姆斯
Earn this.
e辜
Earn it.
e辜大家
"My dear Mrs Ryan."
“H鄣娜鸲魈太”
"It's with a profound sense of joy that I write to inform you"-
“我有喜要Ыo你”
"that your son, Private James Ryan, is well"-
“就是令O二等兵 詹姆斯瑞恩安然o恙”
"and at this moment on his way home from European battlefields."
“F在正W洲的鹁回”
"Reports indicate that James did his duty in combat"-
“詹姆斯M忠守”
"with great courage and steadfast dedication"-
“勇膺^人，砸悴磺”
"even after he was informed of the loss your family has suffered"-
“v使他得悉兄弟亡”
"in this great campaign to rid the world of tyranny and oppression."
“仍猿⑴c@ 除裁暴政的ゴ罂”
"I take great pleasure injoining the Secretary of War, "-
“我c部L”
"the men and women of the US Army, and the citizens of a grateful nation"-
“美同仁及美民”
"in wishing you good health and many years of happiness with James."
“H此祝你身w健康 c詹姆斯一起活得愉快”
"Nothing, not even the safe return of a beloved son"-
“m然圩悠桨w”
"can compensate you or the thousands of other American families"-
“也o法a你 和千千ff美家庭”
"who have suffered great loss in this tragic war."
“在中遭受的痛”
"I might share with you some words"-
“我想c你分享”
"which have sustained me through nights of peril, loss and heartache, "-
“一番在悲痛^望中 支持著我的f”
"and I quote, 'I pray that our heavenly Father"-
“是@拥囊环f”
"may assuage the anguish of your bereavement"-
“天主安崮愕首又痛”
"and leave you only the cherished memory of the loved and lost"-
“你永h涯钸h去的邸
"and the solemn pride that must be yours"-
“神}的s耀都w於你”
"to have laid a so costly a sacrifice upon the altar of freedom."
“因你樽杂 付出了重大的代r”
"Abraham Lincoln."
“林肯敬上”
"Yours very sincerely and respectfully,"-
“深表敬意”
"George C. Marshall. General, Chief of Staff."
“⒅\LR歇上”
My family is with me today. They wanted to come with me.
今天我家人也砹 他想跟我
To be honest with you, I wasn't sure how I would feel coming back here.
f真的，我不知道到@e 有什N感受
Every day, I think about what you said to me that day on the bridge.
我每天都想著 日你在蛏险f的
I've tried to live my life the best I could.
我M力活好我的人生
I hope that was enough.
希望@已足
I hope that at least in your eyes...
希望@至少你X得…
...I've earned what all of you have done for me.
我]有辜 你槲易龅囊磺
James.
詹姆斯
"Captain John H. Miller."
“s翰米勒上尉”
Tell me I have led a good life. What?
跟我f我@子]白活 什N？
Tell me I'm a good man.
跟我f，我是好人
You are.
你是好人